<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>deepakkarki.github.io/blog/</title>
   
   <link>http://deepakkarki.github.io/blog/</link>
   <description>A personal blog on tech, culture, education, and HCI.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Deepak Karki</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Purpose of Education</title>
	  <link>/blog//2017/the-purpose-of-education</link>
	  <author>Deepak Karki</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//2017/the-purpose-of-education</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.</p>

<p>It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.</p>

<p>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking. To think incisively and to think for one’s self is very difficult. We are prone to let our mental life become invaded by legions of half truths, prejudices, and propaganda. At this point, I often wonder whether or not education is fulfilling its purpose. A great majority of the so-called educated people do not think logically and scientifically. Even the press, the classroom, the platform, and the pulpit in many instances do not give us objective and unbiased truths. To save man from the morass of propaganda, in my opinion, is one of the chief aims of education. Education must enable one to sift and weigh evidence, to discern the true from the false, the real from the unreal, and the facts from the fiction.</p>

<p>The function of education, therefore, is to teach one to think intensively and to think critically. But education which stops with efficiency may prove the greatest menace to society. The most dangerous criminal may be the man gifted with reason, but with no morals.</p>

<p>The late Eugene Talmadge, in my opinion, possessed one of the better minds of Georgia, or even America. Moreover, he wore the Phi Beta Kappa key. By all measuring rods, Mr. Talmadge could think critically and intensively; yet he contends that I am an inferior being. Are those the types of men we call educated?</p>

<p>We must remember that intelligence is not enough. Intelligence plus character–that is the goal of true education. The complete education gives one not only power of concentration, but worthy objectives upon which to concentrate. The broad education will, therefore, transmit to one not only the accumulated knowledge of the race but also the accumulated experience of social living.</p>

<p>If we are not careful, our colleges will produce a group of close-minded, unscientific, illogical propagandists, consumed with immoral acts. Be careful, “brethren!” Be careful, teachers!</p>

<p>By <strong>Martin Luther King</strong></p>

<p>An American pastor, activist, humanitarian. People know him for leading the African-American Civil Rights movement using nonviolent civil disobedience.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Businessman & the fisherman</title>
	  <link>/blog//2014/the-businessman-and-fisherman</link>
	  <author>Deepak Karki</author>
	  <pubDate>2014-08-12T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//2014/the-businessman-and-fisherman</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>An American businessman took a vacation to a small coastal Mexican village on doctor’s orders. Unable to sleep after an urgent phone call from the office the first morning, he walked out to the pier to clear his head. A small boat with just one fisherman had docked, and inside the boat were several large yellowfin tuna. The American complimented the Mexican on the quality of his fish.</p>

<p>“How long did it take you to catch them?” the American asked.</p>

<p>“Only a little while,” the Mexican replied in surprisingly good English.</p>

<p>“Why don’t you stay out longer and catch more fish?” the American then asked.</p>

<p>“I have enough to support my family and give a few to friends,” the Mexican said as he unloaded them into a basket.</p>

<p>“But… What do you do with the rest of your time?”</p>

<p>The Mexican looked up and smiled. “I sleep late, fish a little, play with my children, take a siesta with my wife, Julia, and stroll into the village each evening, where I sip wine and play guitar with my amigos. I have a full and busy life, señor.”</p>

<p>The American laughed and stood tall. “Sir, I’m a Harvard M.B.A. and can help you. You should spend more time fishing, and with the proceeds, buy a bigger boat. In no time, you could buy several boats with the increased haul. Eventually, you would have a fleet of fishing boats.”</p>

<p>He continued, “Instead of selling your catch to a middleman, you would sell directly to the consumers, eventually opening your own cannery. You would control the product, processing, and distribution. You would need to leave this small coastal fishing village, of course, and move to Mexico City, then to Los Angeles, and eventually to New York City, where you could run your expanded enterprise with proper management.</p>

<p>The Mexican fisherman asked, “But, señor, how long will all this take?”</p>

<p>To which the American replied, “15-20 years, 25 tops.”</p>

<p>“But what then, señor?”</p>

<p>The American laughed and said, “That’s the best part. When the time is right, you would announce an IPO and sell your company stock to the public and become very rich. You would make millions.”</p>

<p>“Millions señor? Then what?”</p>

<p>“Then you would retire and move to a small coastal fishing village, where you would sleep late, fish a little, play with your kids, take a siesta with your wife, and stroll in to the village in the evenings where you could sip wine and play your guitar with your amigos.”</p>

<p>Adapted from the “Anekdote zur Senkung der Arbeitsmoral” by <strong>Heinrich Böll</strong></p>

<p>An influential German write and Nobel Prize for Literature in 1972.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
